Inventory of the United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service miscellaneous records
1941-1946
58011
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 1,077 sound discs (108.1 linear feet)
Sound recordings of radio broadcasts, and translations of transcripts of Chinese communist broadcasts from Yenan, China. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access; digital copies also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1958.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Historical Note
This service was established by the U.S. government as the Foreign Broadcast Monitoring Service, a unit within the Federal Communications Commission, in February 1941. It recorded, translated, analyzed, and reported to other agencies of the U.S. government on broadcasts of foreign origin. It set up listening posts at Silver Hill, Maryland; London; San Francisco; Portland, Oregon; Kingsville, Texas; San Juan, Puerto Rico; and other places to intercept broadcasts of foreign news, intelligence, or propaganda emanating from authorized stations and clandestine transmitters in belligerent, occupied, and neutral countries.
At the listening posts, translations of the intercepted broadcasts were made and immediately teletyped or cabled to Washington headquarters. Some broadcasts were also recorded on discs. At Washington, incoming wires and transcriptions were edited and the more significant parts, or the full texts, were teletyped to the government agencies that were waging war on the military, diplomatic, and propaganda fronts. Special interpretations and daily and weekly summaries were prepared at headquarters and distributed to appropriate government agencies and officials.
Through cooperative arrangements with the Office of War Information, the British Ministry of Information, and the British Broadcasting Corporation, editors of the service were assigned to overseas posts maintained by those agencies to select material valuable for transmission to Washington. Editors and monitors of the service acted as part of the Army Psychological Warfare Branch in North Africa when Allied troops were landed there in 1943.
On December 30, 1945, the service was transferred to the War Department, and in 1946 the functions of the service were transferred to the Central Intelligence Agency.
Source: National Archives and Records Service. Federal Records of World War II. Vol. 1, Civilian Agencies. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1950.
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recordings of radio broadcasts, and translations of transcripts of Chinese communist broadcasts from Yenan, China.
Propaganda, Communist--China.; Radio broadcasting.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; Sound recordings.
- Sound Recordings, 1941-1946
  - State-sponsored broadcasts, 1942-1944
    Scope and Contents note
    Sound recordings of Radio Tokyo, Voice of China, Australian radio, and Thai radio.
    - Audio letter home from prisoner-of-war Martin A. Ravansky, 1942 December 7 (Record cabinet)
    - Australian radio and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, numbers 187-188, 1942 June 14 (Record cabinet)
    - Australian and Radio Tokyo radio transmissions, 1942 March 16-17 (Record cabinet)
    - Australian radio and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 March 21-22 (Record cabinet)
      Side A label reads:
      AUST, 430A, 3/21
      TK, 5A, 3/21
      Side B label reads:
      MEL, 430A, 3/22/42
      TK, 500A, 3/22/42
    - Australian radio and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 March 23 (Record cabinet)
      Australian radio provides an update on the Allied forces in the Pacific Theater.
    - Australian radio and Voice of China broadcasts, numbers 209-210, 1942 April 3 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #209, Australia
      Part 2: #209, Voice of China
      Part 3: #210, Australia, 1201A
      Part 4: #210, Australia, 700A
    - Australian radio transmissions, 1942 March 28 and 30 (Record cabinet)
      AUST
      430A
      3/28/42
      3/30/42
    - Australian radio, Radio Tokyo, Voice of China, and London Calling broadcasts, numbers 173-174, 1942 June 22 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #173, Australia
      Part 2: #173, Australia
      Part 3: #173, Radio Tokyo
      Part 4: #174, Voice of China
      Part 5: #174, London Calling
      Part 6: #174, Radio Tokyo
    - Australian radio, Radio Tokyo, and Voice of China broadcasts, 1942 March 25 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Australia, 430A
      Radio Tokyo, 500A
      Part 2: Voice of China 745A, 800A
      The 745A broadcast is two articles, the first about U.S. General Stilwell, and the second about the conflict between China and Japan.
    - Australian radio, Radio Tokyo, and Voice of China broadcasts, numbers 159-160, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #159, Australia
      Part 2: #159, Radio Tokyo makes the case for America being the aggressor in the Pacific, citing economic sanctions and American internal memos prior to the Pearl Harbor bombing. It then goes on to a general news roundup.
      Part 3: #160, Australia
      Part 4: #160, Radio Tokyo
      Part 5: #160, Voice of China news roundup; includes a segment about Chiang Kai-Shek's crackdown on opium smoking, blaming the problem on the Japanese.
    - Australian radio, Radio Tokyo, and Voice of China broadcasts, numbers 167-168, 1942 June 20 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #167, Australian news roundup
      Part 2: #167, Radio Tokyo broadcasts messages home of American POWs
      Part 3: #167
      Part 4: #167, Voice of China
      Part 5: #168, Radio Tokyo news roundup
      Part 6: #168, Voice of China
    - Australian, Radio Tokyo, and Voice of China radio broadcasts during World War II, 1941 (Record cabinet)
      Inside sounds like Australia
      Outside - Japan war prisoners
      CK
      800A
      3/26/41
    - Australian, Voice of China, and Radio Tokyo transmissions, 1942 April 25 (Record cabinet)
      Chungking
      Australia fades into Chungking
      Outside Tokyo #239
      Apr 25, 1942
      Australia
      Toko
      Australia #240
      Apr 1942
    - B. Bowe broadcast recording, 1942 November 23 (Record cabinet)
      Recording of a radio broadcast from the airwaves.
    - Bangkok radio broadcast, 1943 March 21 (Record cabinet)
    - Broadcasting Corporation of Japan radio transmissions, 1942 January 15-February 16 (Record cabinet)
      Radio transmissions concerning military conflicts in Southeast Asia, especially the fall of Singapore to the Japanese. These broadcasts were recorded onto lacquer disc from airwaves.
      Side A label reads: #105 TK, 1030P, 1-15-42 TK, 500A, 1-16-42 CK, 700A, 1-16-42
    - Chungking, Australian, and Tokyo radio transmission, 1942 June (Record cabinet)
      Various news radio broadcasts from Chungking, Australia, and Tokyo.
    - Coded radio transmissions and Radio Saigon broadcast, 1942 February 20 (Record cabinet)
      #87, Code-this face, 2/20/42
    - Coded radio transmissions and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 23 and March 20 (Record cabinet)
      PMA, 430P
      TK, 710P
      TK(1), 8:30P
      2-23-42
      2, DLV, 800A, 2-23-42
      TK, 400P, 2-23-42
      1, TK, 400P, 3/20/42
    - Coded radio transmissions and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 18-20 (Record cabinet)
      #81, PMA, 430P, 2-18-42
      Side B label reads
      #82
      TK, 830P, 2-18-42
      TK, 400P, 2-20-42
    - Coded radio transmissions, Voice of China broadcast, and Radio Tokyo broadcast, 1942 February 18 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Coded signals from 800A, 2-18-42
      Part 2:
      Voice of China broadcasts articles for the United Press.
      Radio Tokyo broadcasts letters home from American prisoners-of-war.
    - Coded signal and Radio Tokyo transmissions, 1942 February 19-21 (Record cabinet)
      PMA, 430P, 2/19/42
      Translation
      TK, 400P, 2-21-42
      CK, 700A, 2-20-42
      TK, 1030P, 2-20-42
      TK, 830P, 2-21-42
      TK, 1030P, 2-21-42
    - Coded signal and Voice of China radio transmissions, 1942 February 24- 25 (Record cabinet)
      PMA 1
      430P
      2-24-42
      PMA, 430P, 2-24-42
      3, CH, 700A, 2-25-42
    - Coded signal radio transmissions from 17 February and Radio Tokyo broadcasts from 18 February, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      Side A is coded signal transmissions.
      Side B is Radio Tokyo broadcasts.
    - Coded signal radio transmissions sound recordings, 1942 February 21 (Record cabinet)
      #91 PMA 1 Code
      2-21-42
      #92 PMA 2 Code
    - Coded signal transmissions and Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcast sound recordings, 1941 February 20-21 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Recording No. 85, PMA, 430P, 2 Feb 1941
      Side B: Recording No. 86, Tokyo, 500A, and Chungking, 700A, 21 Feb 1942
    - Coded signal transmissions from 19 February and Radio Tokyo broadcasts from 20 February, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      #89, PLV, 800A, 2-19-42
      #90
      2, Code Inside, PLV, 801A, 2-19-42
      Outside 2, TK, 830P, 2-20-42
    - East Asian broadcasts, 1942 March 6-7 (Record cabinet)
      Access
      Use copy reference number: 58011_a_0001770
      Side A cut 1 is a news broadcast about the Asian theater of World War II. Cut 2 is a reading of the text of speeches by such figures as Chiang Kai-shek.
      Side B cut 1 is a broadcast of the Broadcasting Corporation of Japan. Cut 2 is a Voice of China broadcast.
    - National Broadcasting Company reading of General Wainwright's order on the surrender of the Philippines, 1942 May 5 (Record cabinet)
      This recording is a reading of General Jonathan M. Wainwright's order of surrender to his soldiers.
    - News roundup of Chinese response to Japanese advances and battles, 1942 June (Record cabinet)
      Voice of China provides an update on the Chinese and Japanese armed forces' conflicts, prisoners taken, and counts of casualties.
      Following is a synopsis of Chiang Kai-Shek's visit to the Chinese central military academy or its "West Point," as the journalist calls it. It was the 18th anniversary of the founding of the academy.
    - PLV coded signals and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 March 3 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: PLV, 3 Mar 1942
      Part 2: Radio Tokyo, 3 Mar 1942, 500A
      Part 3: Radio Tokyo, 3 Mar 1942, 400P. Messages home from American POWs.
      Part 4: Radio Tokyo, 13 Mar 1942, 400P
    - Radio Bangkok and Radio Tokyo broadcast recordings, 1942 October 14 (Record cabinet)
    - Radio Bangkok broadcast recording, 1942 October 13 (Record cabinet)
      Recording from the airwaves of Radio Bangkok and Radio Tokyo transmitting in Thai to Thailand.
    - Radio Bangkok broadcasts sound recording, 1943 May 13 (Record cabinet)
      Label reads:
      No. B 1
      DATE 5/13/43 TIME 6:04-6:15, 6:19-6:31
      PROGRAM over for rest
      FROM Bangkok
    - Radio Chungking and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 11 (Record cabinet)
      Side A is about the prices of goods and smuggling in Japan-controlled China.
      Side B is a reading of letters home from American POWs held by Japan.
    - Radio Chungking and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 13 and 16 (Record cabinet)
    - Radio Chungking and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 17 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Recording No. 31, Radio Chungking.
      Part 2: Recording No. 32, Radio Tokyo.
    - Radio Chungking and Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 21-22 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Recording No. 47, Radio Chungking, 7:00 News, Radio Tokyo, 7:30P, 21 Jan 1942
      Side B: Recording No. 48, Radio Tokyo, 930P, and Radio Chungking, 600A, 22 Jan 1942
    - Radio Chungking broadcast from 14 January and Radio Tokyo broadcast from 15 January, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Recording No. 51, Chungking
      Part 2: Recording No. 52, Tokyo
      No. 51 possibly also contains a radio broadcast from Australia.
    - Radio Chungking broadcasts, 1942 January 18 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #33 Radio Chungking, 18 Jan 1942, 700AM
      Part 2: #34 Radio Chungking, 18 Jan 1942
    - Radio Chungking broadcasts, 1942 January 20 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Recording No. 41, Chungking, 600AM
      Side B: Recording No. 42, Chungking, 700AM
    - Radio Saigon, Radio Tokyo, and Voice of China broadcasts, 1942 January 23-March 20 (Record cabinet)
      Organizations from Saigon and Tokyo offer, in English, news updates regarding the war.
      Part 1 (Side A):
      Radio Saigon, 23 Jan 1942
      Part 2 (Side A):
      Radio Tokyo, 17 Mar 1942
      Radio Tokyo, 20 Mar 1942
      Part 3 (Side B):
      Voice of China from Chungking, 700A, 23 Jan 1942
      Radio Tokyo, 830A, 20 Mar 1942
    - Radio Saigon, Radio Tokyo, and Voice of China transmissions, 1942 January 13 (Record cabinet)
      These transmissions concern the Pacific Theater of World War II.
    - Radio Tokyo and Australian radio broadcasts, 1942 January 22 (Record cabinet)
      Parts 1: Radio Tokyo, 6:10PM, 22 January 1942. A news/propaganda roundup, the anchor reads a proclamation about why Burma should ally with Japan. This is followed by messages home from American POW Major Putnam of Coronado, California.
      Part 2: Unidentified radio broadcast about developments in the Pacific Theater of World War II.
      Part 3: Radio Tokyo news roundup and messages home from American POWs.
      Part 4: Melbourne, 7:30AM. A news roundup.
      Part 5: Dead air and a short clip of music.
    - Radio Tokyo and Australian radio broadcasts numbers 185-186, 1941-1946 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #185, Radio Tokyo. A news roundup followed by messages home from American POWs.
      Part 2: #185, Australia
      Part 3: #186, Radio Tokyo followed by Voice of China
    - Radio Tokyo and Australian radio broadcasts, numbers 145-146, 1942 May 27-28 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Radio Tokyo broadcasts messages home from American POWs. One is from San Mateo, CA, and the other from Washington, DC. Sound quality is exceptionally poor.
      Part 2: Australia
      Part 3: Australia / Messages home from American POWs in Japan
      Part 4: Messages home from American POWs in Japan
      Part 5: Noises
      Part 6: Unidentified story about raft survival.
      Part 7: Australia
    - Radio Tokyo and Australian radio transmissions, 1942 March 27 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Radio Tokyo and Australian radio transmissions from 27 Mar 1942
      Side B: Undated Australian transmissions.
    - Radio Tokyo and Radio Chungking broadcasts, 1942 January 13-14 (Record cabinet)
      Includes two recordings (parts 2 and 4) that are completely unrelated to radio transmissions (a recordist's family recordings).
    - Radio Tokyo and Radio Chungking broadcasts, 1942 January 14 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Recording No. 23
      Radio Tokyo provides news and analysis concerning the war against the UK, USA, and in the Pacific in general.
      Side B: Recording No. 24
      Radio Chungking provides a news roundup.
    - Radio Tokyo and Radio Chungking broadcasts, 1942 January 22 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Recording No. 45, Radio Tokyo, 4AM, 22 Jan 1942
      Side B: Recording No. 46, Radio Tokyo, 645A, and Radio Chungking, 700A, 22 Jan 1942
    - Radio Tokyo and Radio Chungking broadcasts, 1942 February 22-23 (Record cabinet)
      On side A, Radio Tokyo provides an update on the war. In the process, it describes the failure of American attacks against Japan and recalls events in Burma, Hong Kong, Chungking, and Thailand. It calls for India to rise up against British imperialism.
      Side B is news and analysis from Radio Chungking.
    - Radio Tokyo and Radio Chungking broadcasts, 1942 January 22-23 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Recording No. 57. Radio Tokyo, 9:30PM and 6:45AM on 22 Jan 1942, and 300PM on 23 Jan 1942
      Side B: Recording No. 58. Radio Tokyo, 1:00AM, and Radio Chungking, 6:00AM, 23 Jan 1942
    - Radio Tokyo and Radio Chungking transmissions, 1942 March 12-13 (Record cabinet)
      Radio Tokyo focuses on India, the United States, the United Kingdom, and Japan.
      Radio Chungking focuses on China, but sounds like the transmissions were jammed by a third party.
    - Radio Tokyo and Radio Saigon broadcasts, 1942 January 12 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Radio Tokyo, 12 Jan 1942, 3:00PM.
      Part 2: Radio Saigon, 12 Jan 1942
      Radio Tokyo provides an update of Japanese military advances throughout the Pacific. Radio Saigon broadcasts a general international news report.
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcasts, 1942 February 15 (Record cabinet)
      Radio Tokyo and Voice of China report on the fighting in the Pacific Theater of World War II.
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcasts, 1942 February 19 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Radio Tokyo presents the news on the evening of 19 Feb 1942
      Part 2: The Voice of China comments on an address by Chiang Kai-Shek on the New Life Movement.
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcasts, 1942 March 3 and 5 (Record cabinet)
      TK, 400P, 3/3/42
      TK, 610P, 3/3/42
      TK, 710P, 3/3/42
      TK, 830P, 3/5/42
      TK, 500A, 3-5-42
      CK, 800A, 3-5-42
      TK, 4P, 3-5-42
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcasts, 1942 January 31 and March 28 (Record cabinet)
      #103
      TOKYO, 610P, 1-31-42
      TOKYO, 730P, 1/31/42
      TK, 710P, 3/28/42
      #104
      CK, 700A, 1-31-42
      TOKYO, 300P, 1-31-42
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcasts, numbers 121-122, 1942 February 3 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Unidentified, possibly the Voice of China.
      Part 2: #121, Radio Tokyo, 645A
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcasts, numbers 129-130, circa 1942 February 5-6 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #129, Tokyo, 645A, 2-5-42
      Part 2: #129, Tokyo, 610P, 2-6-45
      Part 3: #130, Chungking, 700A, 2-5-42
      (The 1945 date is possibly a typo found on the original disc label.)
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China broadcasts, numbers 141-142, 1942 February 13-14 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #141, Radio Tokyo, 13 Feb 1942, 11:30PM. Concerns Singapore and other locations in Southeast Asia.
      Part 2: #141, Radio Tokyo, 14 Feb 1942, 2:00A.
      Part 3: #141, Radio Tokyo, 14 Feb 1942, 5:00A.
      Part 4: #142, Voice of China, 14 Feb 1942, probably 6:00AM. This broadcast was heavily jammed, and the disc groove was considerably worn. Both contribute to significantly reduced sound quality.
      Part 5: #142, Radio Tokyo, undated. Additional news coverage of action in Southeast Asia.
      Part 6: Morse code?
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China radio broadcasts, 1942 March 3-6 (Record cabinet)
      2 PLV, 800A, 3-3-42
      TK TK, 500A, 3-4-42
      2 CK, 800A, 3-6-42
      TK, 710PM, 3-6-42
      CK UP
      730A
      3-4-42
    - Radio Tokyo and Voice of China radio broadcasts, numbers 125 and 126, 1942 February 4 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Radio Tokyo, recording #125, 4 Feb 1942, 400A
      Part 2: Voice of China, recording #126, 4 Feb 1942, 600A
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 11 (Record cabinet)
      10:30 PWT - 11:00 PWT
      These English-language broadcasts concern the Japanese advances on Singapore, Vietnam, Shanghai, and other locations in Asia. It focuses on how Japan is beating both the United States and the United Kingdom in the war.
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 12-13 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: 12 Jan 1942, 7:30 PM
      Part 2: 13 Jan 1942, 1:00 AM
      Radio Tokyo gives an update on the war. It describes the advances of the Japanese forces throughout the Pacific.
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 15 (Record cabinet)
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 16-17, March 29 (Record cabinet)
      TK, 400P, 2-16-42
      TK, 710P, 2-16-42
      TK, 400P, 3/29/42
      TK, 500A, 2-17-42
      CK, 700A, 2-17-42
      Radio Tokyo gives updates on the war and reads letters home from American prisoners-of-war.
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 February 19 and 21 (Record cabinet)
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts from 2 March and Voice of China broadcast from 3 March, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Radio Tokyo provides an update of the war before reading letters home from American prisoners-of-war.
      Part 2: Radio Tokyo provides an update on the war against the Allies, focusing on the Dutch East Indies.
      Part 3: Voice of China comments on the fighting in the Dutch East Indies before speaking about issues concerning Korea.
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 23-24, March 17 (Record cabinet)
      Side A (Parts 1-3), label reads:
      TOKYO, 9:30PM ALSO PofW, 1-23-42
      T, 730P, 1-24-42
      Side B (Parts 4- ), label reads:
      1
      TOKYO, 100A, 1-24-42
      TK, 610P, 3/17/42
      TK, 730P, 3/17/42
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 25-26 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: Recording No. 61, 300PM, 610 PM, 25 Jan 1942
      This recording concerns the declaration of war of Thailand against the UK and USA.
      Side B: Recording No. 62, 100am, 26 Jan 1942
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 January 7 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Recording No. 49, 6:45A and 7:30P
      Part 2: Recording No. 50, 3:00P
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, 1942 March 7-8 (Record cabinet)
      Sound quality is poor throughout.
      In the first cut on side A, Radio Tokyo reads letters home from American prisoners-of-war.
      The second and third cuts are news roundups of Japan's advances in the Pacific.
      Side B features similar programs in three cuts.
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts from 9 and 10 March and Voice of China broadcast from 10 March, 1942 (Record cabinet)
      TK, 710P, 3/9/42
      TK, 500A, 3/10/42
      TK, 830P, 3/10/42
      CK, 8A, 3/10/42
      TK, 4p, 3/10/42
      TK, 710P, 3/10/42
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, numbers 11-12, 1942 January 9 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: #11, 3:00PM. A news roundup of the Japanese advances against British and American forces in various locations, mostly in Southeast Asia.
      Part 2: #12, 7:30PM. A news roundup.
    - Radio Tokyo broadcasts, numbers 119-120, 1942 February 2 (Record cabinet)
      Parts 1-3: TOKYO, 300P, 2-2-42
      Parts 4-5: TOKYO, 600P, 2-2-42
    - Radio Tokyo in Thai, 1942 April 14 (Record cabinet)
    - Radio Tokyo radio transmissions, 1942 February 8 (Record cabinet)
      Side A: In the first cut, an announcer for Radio Tokyo reads, in English, the names of captured American soldiers and their messages to loved ones back home.
      The second cut is nearly intelligible due to reception issues cut into the disc groove.
      The third cut recounts advances of Japanese forces before returning to the list of captured Americans.
      Side B: An anchor reports the advances of the Japanese forces.